Harold Spivacke Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Harold Spivacke Collection 1923-1984 (bulk 1930-1978)
ML31.S69
Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977
around 3,900 items 33 containers 13 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Harold Spivacke was a music librarian, administrator, musicologist, and musician. He was chief of the Library of Congress Music Division for thirty-five years, from 1937 until 1972. The collection contains materials relating to his life and career, including correspondence, student notebooks, speeches, his dissertation, photographs, clippings, programs, manuscript and printed music, artwork, awards and honorary degrees, and business papers.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Albert, Eugen d', 1864-1932--Photographs.; Angell, Richard--Correspondence.; Anglès, Higini, 1888-1969--Correspondence.; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990--Correspondence.; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953--Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975--Correspondence.; Downes, Olin, 1886-1955--Correspondence.; Downes, Olin,1886-1955--Photographs.; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955--Photographs.; Einstein, Alfred, 1880-1952--Photographs.; Engel, Carl, 1883-1944--Correspondence.; Gershwin, Ira, 1896-1983--Photographs.; Ginastera, Alberto, 1916-1983--Correspondence.; Ginastera, Alberto, 1916-1983--Photographs.; Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961--Photographs.; Grentzer, Rose Marie--Correspondence.; Grentzer, Rose Marie--Photographs.; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979--Correspondence.; Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-1987--Correspondence.; Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966--Correspondence.; Kinkeldey, Otto, 1878-1966--Photographs.; Malipiero, Riccardo, 1914-2003--Correspondence.; Miller, Dayton Clarence, 1866-1941--Correspondence.; Oberdoerffer, Fritz--Correspondence.; Saul, Patrick--Photographs.; Siegmeister, Elie, 1909-1991--Correspondence.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977--Archives.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977--Correspondence.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977--Photographs.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977. Ueber die objektive und subjektive Toninten ität.; Stern, Isaac, 1920-2001--Correspondence.; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971--Correspondence.; Whittall, Gertrude Clarke, 1867-1965--Correspondence.; Whittall, Gertrude Clarke, 1867-1965--Photographs.
Organizations
Budapest String Quartet--Photographs.; Library of Congress. Music Division.; London String Quartet--Photographs.
Subjects
Music librarians--United States.; Music--Manuscripts.; Music--United States--20th century.
Form/Genre
Artifacts (Object genre); Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents)
Administrative Information
Provenance
Acquired by the Library of Congress from the estate of Mrs. Harold Spivacke in Sept. 1986.
Custodial History
After Harold Spivacke's death in 1977, Mrs. Spivacke donated materials to the Library of Congress. In 1978, she gave a violin bow made for Fritz Kreisler by W. E. Hill & Sons of London, which now is part of the musical instruments collections in the Music Division. She gave additional items in 1979, including twenty-six shellac disc recordings, mostly of ethnic music, which now reside in the Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, and three pen and ink sketches of floral arrangements by Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, signed and dated 1898, which are part of the Music Division's Harold Spivacke Collection.
In 1982, Mrs. Spivacke established the Rose Marie and Harold Spivacke Fund Collection in the Music Division at the Library of Congress. The purpose of this endowment is to assist the Library with the acquisition of books, manuscripts, and other materials for the collections of the Music Division.
Harold Spivacke's 1929 passport was a gift from Robinson's Thrift Shop and added to the Harold Spivacke Collection in 1987.
During Mr. Spivacke's tenure as chief of the Library of Congress Music Division, he donated an assortment of music manuscripts and printed scores, which were catalogued and made part of the general collections; sound recordings, which are housed in Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division; and other printed material.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Sound recordings, including an audio cassette of Patrick Hayes' broadcast in Spivacke's honor, have been transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division.
Related Material
The materials in the Spivacke Fund (Rose Marie and Harold Spivacke) Collection have been purchased through an endowment fund established by Mrs. Harold Spivacke in 1982, based on the wishes of her husband. The purpose of the fund is to assist the Library of Congress in adding to and increasing the collections in the Music Division. The purchases primarily focus on holograph music manuscripts, printed music, and autograph correspondence which enhance the existing collections.
Access and Restrictions
The Harold Spivacke Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Harold Spivacke was born July 18, 1904 in New York City. He studied at New York University, where he received his B.A. in 1923 and his M.A. in 1924. He attended the University of Berlin and received his Ph.D. in 1933, magna cum laude, with the dissertation Über die objektive und subjektive Tonintensität (Beyond Objective and Subjective Tonal Intensity). During this time, he also studied music privately with Henry Levey in New York and Eugen d'Albert and Hugo Leichtentritt in Berlin.
After finishing his dissertation in 1933, Spivacke returned to New York City, where he began work as a research assistant to Olin Downes, a well-known music critic for the New York Times. While assisting Mr. Downes, it was discovered, and confirmed by Fritz Kreisler, that some compositions performed by Kreisler and attributed to such composers as Vivaldi, Couperin, Pugnani and others, were actually composed by Kreisler himself.
In 1934, Spivacke moved to Washington to become the assistant chief of the Music Division at the Library of Congress. After three years, he was promoted to chief of the Music Division (1937), in which capacity he worked for thirty-five years until his retirement in 1972. During his tenure, the holdings of the Music Division almost tripled and the activities and services of the division were significantly expanded. The Library's Coolidge Auditorium chamber music programs grew under Spivacke's tenure, with the help of the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge and Gertrude Clarke Whittall foundations, established before 1937, and later by the Serge Koussevitzky Music Foundation and the McKim Fund, established in 1949 and 1970 respectively. It was also during the Spivacke era that the Library continued to commission and perform works by contemporary composers through these foundations and to acquire manuscripts from such noted composers and musicians as Richard Rodgers, George and Ira Gershwin, Jelly Roll Morton, Charlie Parker, Igor Stravinsky, and Arnold Schoenberg.
During his service to the Library of Congress, Spivacke held numerous advisory positions with various government agencies, including the Department of State, the Joint Army and Navy Committee on Recreation and Welfare, UNESCO, and the Pan American Union. He was also an active member of many professional organizations, including the National Music Council, the Music Library Association, the International Association of Music Libraries, and the American Musicological Society. He received honorary degrees from Baldwin-Wallace College in 1947, the University of Rochester in 1955, and the Cleveland Institute of Music in 1969. Throughout his career, he received numerous awards for his contributions to the fields of musicology and librarianship.
Harold Spivacke was married in 1927 to Carolyn Le Fèvre, a concert violinist with whom he had two sons, Joseph L. and Robert C. Spivacke. They were divorced in 1953. In 1955, he married Rose Marie Grentzer, a noted teacher and choral conductor. Harold and Rose Marie remained married until his death in Washington on May 19, 1977, at the age of 72. Rose Marie Spivacke died on November 11, 1985.
Scope and Content Note
The Harold Spivacke Collection spans the years 1923 to 1984, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1930 to 1978. The collection reflects the life of a musicologist, music librarian, and administrator of the Music Division of the Library of Congress. It includes his doctoral dissertation and student notebooks, correspondence with composers and colleagues in the fields of musicology and librarianship, awards and honorary degrees, manuscript and printed music, programs, clippings, artwork, photographs, and papers and printed matter from his numerous associations.
The Correspondence series contains both personal and business-related correspondence, dating from 1924 to 1984. The correspondence spans his adult life and reflects his friendships with musicologists, librarians, and musicians. It includes letters from Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, Gertrude Clarke Whittall, Jascha Heifetz, Leonard Bernstein (photo-greeting cards), Aaron Copland, Carl Engel, Otto Kinkeldey, Luigi Dallapiccola, Dayton C. Miller, Isaac Stern (photo-greeting cards), Riccardo Malipiero, Roy Harris, Elie Siegmeister, Higini Anglès, Richard Angell, Igor Stravinsky, and many other notable figures from the worlds of music and music librarianship. There is extensive correspondence with the composer Alberto Ginastera, the music critic Olin Downes, and Fritz Oberdörffer, a friend from Spivacke's student days in Berlin who Spivacke assisted in his efforts to leave Germany around the time of the Second World War.
The Writings series contains representative material from Spivacke's studies at the University of Berlin, his dissertation Über die objektive und subjektive Tonintensität (Beyond Objective and Subjective Tonal Intensity), and student notebooks. Other materials include essays, notes for speeches and presentations, writings about Spivacke by others, and a number of articles and essays dealing with music.
The Photographs series includes official and professional photoprints of Spivacke, notable individuals, and friends and family. There are photoprints, some of which are signed, of Gertrude Clarke Whittall, Patrick Saul, Olin Downes, Otto Kinkeldey, Alberto Ginastera, Ira Gershwin, Percy Grainger, and several performing groups, including the Budapest and London string quartets. In addition, there are photographs of Albert and Alfred Einstein, Eugen d'Albert, family portraits of Spivacke with his wife Rose Marie, and a large number of scenic shots of Spivacke's home and from trips to Europe, including two photo albums dating from 1929-1930.
The Artwork series includes small watercolors by Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge, a charcoal portrait of Spivacke from 1929 by George Beline, and a reproduction of a charcoal portrait of Spivacke's first wife, Carolyn Le Fèvre, also by Beline. The Music series includes holograph scores inscribed to Harold Spivacke and signed by Luigi Dallapiccola and Riccardo Malipiero. Other materials in the collection include printed programs from various concerts, clippings and other printed matter, numerous awards and medals, and a few financial and legal papers, primarily dating from his days in Germany.
Arielle J. Siebert and Wilda M. Heiss, 1995-1996
Organization of the Harold Spivacke Collection
The Harold Spivacke Collection is organized in eleven series:
Writings, 1923-1972
Correspondence, 1923-1984
Subject File, 1925-1977
Legal and Financial, 1923-1974
Programs, 1924-1984
Clippings, 1933-1984
Realia, 1923-1974
Photographs, 1928-1975
Artwork, 1927-1947
Music, 1943-1971
Printed Matter, 1929-1977
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006572324
Container List
- Writings, 1923-1972, undated, (6 boxes) (Box 1-5, 27)
  Manuscript, typescript, mimeograph, negative photostat, and printed materials; published and unpublished; includes lectures, speeches, and notes about music, and musical examples.
  - Writings by Spivacke (Box 1-4, 27)
    Manuscript, typescript, mimeograph, negative photostat, and printed materials; published and unpublished; includes lectures, speeches, and notes about music.
    Arranged alphabetically by title or topic.
    - Abstracts for musicologists, 1968 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Acoustics and physiology, undated (Box-folder 1/2-3)
    - Acoustics, miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Aesthetics / Kant, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Basic concepts in music education, 1958 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Broadcasting sound archives and scholarly research, undated (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Calculations and graphs, undated (Box-folder 1/9)
    - "C" miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Deutsches Lied, undated (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Dissertation: Über die objektive und subjektive Tonintensität, 1933, undated see also Über die objektive und subjektive Tonintensität [microfilm] (Box-folder 2/3-5)
    - Dissertation I [notebook], undated (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Dissertation II [notebook], undated (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Dissertation II [notebook]: Carl Stumpf - Stärkeschätzungen, undated (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Dissertation III [notebook], undated (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Die Dissonanz Erscheinung in Palestrina's Stabat Mater, undated (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Einfürhrung in die Musikwissenschaft, undated (Box-folder 2/11)
    - "E-K" miscellaneous (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Geschichte der Kammer und Orchestermusik, undated (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Klaviermusik, undated (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Library of Congress Music Division, undated (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Lizst und Wagner, undated (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Meusural notation - proseminar, undated (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Metaphysik / Gestalt psychology, undated (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Music in international relations, undated (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Music librarianship: a practical guide, 1961 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Musik der vorchristlichen Zeit, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Musik des Renaissance und Baroks, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - National archive of sound recordings, 1963 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Notes on countries, undated (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Notes on music, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Notes on music, undated (Box-folder 3/8-9)
    - Notes on music / composers, A-B (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Notes on music / composers, C-H (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Notes on music / composers, J-L (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Notes on music / composers, M (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Notes on music / composers, P-R (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Notes on music / composers, S-W (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Notes on music / composers, Miscellaneous (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Philosophie der Kunst, undated (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Place of acoustics in musicology, 1936 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Present status of copyright revision bill, 1968 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Preservation and reference services of sound recording in a research library, undated (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Psychologie der Gehörserscheinungen, undated (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Psychology, general, undated (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Research library of sound recordings, 1960 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Role of music librarian, 1971 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Student notes with musical examples (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Tone intensity - definitions and measurement of, undated (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Über die objektive und subjektive Tonintensität [microfilm], 1933 see also Dissertation (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Vergleighende Musikwissenschaft, undated (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Violin lecture-recitals, 1933, undated see also Music, Miscellaneous. Notebook of music for violin and piano (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Volksgesang, undated (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Wegel and Lane, Verhüllung, 1923 (Box-folder 4/13)
  - Writings by Others (Box 5)
    Manuscript, typescript, mimeograph, negative photostats, and printed materials, including musical examples.
    Arranged alphabetically by author and by title therein.
    - "A-F" miscellaneous (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Balbulus, Notker. Sequence verse types from Isaac's "Choralis constantinus," undated (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Barbour, J. Murray. Irregular systems of temperament, undated (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Hannas, Ruth. Notes for paper on Telemann, undated (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Hayes, Patrick. Broadcast on Juilliard String Quartet, 1971 Oct. 31 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Hayes, Patrick. Broadcast on Harold Spivacke, 1972 Feb. 13 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Hirt, Charles C. Greek-Slavic musical examples, undated (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Kuypers, John M. Second string quartet, Charles Ives, undated (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Riemenschneider, Albert. Presentation speeches of honorary doctor of music degree to Harold Spivacke at Baldwin-Wallace College, 1947 see also Correspondence, Baldwin-Wallace College; Correspondence, Riemenschneider, Albert; Realia, Baldwin-Wallace College (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Spivacke, Charles A. Asthma with pneumothorax, 1925 Jul. 1 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Spivacke, Charles A. Treatment of hay fever, 1925 Aug. 19 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Wegel, R. L. and C. E. Lane. Auditory masking of one pure tone by another... [also in German], undated (Box-folder 5/11)
- Correspondence, 1923-1984, undated, (8 boxes) (Box 5-11, 33)
  Manuscript and typescript letters, telegrams, retirement album to Harold Spivacke, and condolence letters to Rose Marie Spivacke upon the death of Harold.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent, and chronologically therein.
  - Achron, Joseph, 1934 (Box-folder 5/12)
  - Adnaufaygŭnf, A., undated (Box-folder 5/13)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1951 (Box-folder 5/14)
  - American Council of Learned Societies Convention, 1952 (Box-folder 5/15)
  - American Council of Learned Societies Russian Translation Project, undated (Box-folder 33/1)
  - American German Student Exchange, Inc., 1929, undated (Box-folder 5/16)
  - American Musicological Association, 1933-1972 (Box-folder 5/17)
  - American Society for Comparative Musicology, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Angell, Richard, 1934-1977 (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Anglès, Higini, 1962 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Association Internationale des Bibliothèques Musicales, 1960-1973, undated (Box-folder 6/4)
  - "A" miscellaneous (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Babbitt, Milton, 1967 (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Baldwin-Wallace College, 1947-1977, undated see also Correspondence, Riemenschneider, Albert; Writings by Others, Riemenschneider, Albert; Realia, Baldwin-Wallace College (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Bennett, Robert Russell, 1972 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1962-1977, undated (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Biggs, E. Power, 1972 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Bradley, Carol June, 1974-1975, undated (Box-folder 6/11)
  - "B" miscellaneous (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Carpenter, Ellen (Mrs. John Alden), 1952 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Chase, Gilbert, 1948 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., 1958, undated (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, A-B, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, C-D, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, E-F, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/18)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, G-I, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/19)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, J-L, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/20)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, M, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/21)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, N-P, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/22)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, R, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/23)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, S-T, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/24)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, U-Z, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/25)
  - Condolences to Rose Marie Spivacke, Unidentified, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 6/26)
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1946, undated (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Coolidge, Sprague and Peg, undated (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1966-1977 see also Retirement album and Retirement correspondence (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Cowell, Sidney Robertson, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - "C" miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Dahl, Ingolf, 1968 (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Dallapiccola, Luigi and Laura, 1945-1972, undated see also Retirement album and Stevenson, Robert (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Davison, Archibald and Kathleen, 1933-1955 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Deis, Carl, undated (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Downes, Olin, 1934-1955, undated (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Downes, Olin, Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 7/13)
  - "D" miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Eastman School of Music, 1933-1962 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Engel, Carl, 1933-1943 see also Library of Congress (Box-folder 7/16)
  - "E" miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Fassett, James H. see Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.
  - Finney, Ross Lee, 1955 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Funk-Stunde Aktiengesellschaft, 1930 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - "F" miscellaneous (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Gershwin, Ira and Lee, 1965-1981, undated (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Ginastera, Alberto and Aurora, 1972-1983, undated (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Ginastera, Alberto and Mercedes, 1959-1975, undated (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Goldman, Edwin Franko, 1943 (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Goldman, Richard Franko, 1977 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Greeting cards, A-K (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Greeting cards, L-Z (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Greeting cards, Unidentified (Box-folder 8/3)
  - "G" miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Halffter, Cristóbal, 1975 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Hanson, Howard see Eastman School of Music
  - Harris, Roy and Johanna, 1963-1972, undated (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Heckmann, Harald, 1964-1977 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Heifetz, Jascha, undated (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Hill, Edward, 1933 (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 1972 (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Hoboken, Anthony and Eva van, 1955-1975 (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Howe, Mary, 1955 (Box-folder 8/12)
  - "H" miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/13)
  - International Musicological Society - Eighth Congress, 1961, undated (Box-folder 8/14)
  - "I" miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Jeppesen, Knud, 1965 (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Joint Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation see Realia, War Department and Navy Department
  - "J" miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Kelly, Walt, 1956 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1969 (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1964 (Box-folder 8/20)
  - King, Alec Hyatt, 1960-1977 (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Kinkeldey, Otto, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 8/22)
  - Kolchin, Betty, 1939-1978 (Box-folder 8/23)
  - Kostelanetz, André, 1960-1977, undated see also Retirement album (Box-folder 8/24)
  - Koussevitzky, Olga (Mrs. Serge), 1955, undated (Box-folder 8/25)
  - "K" miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/26)
  - Le Fèvre, Carolyn, 1923-1928, undated see also same entry under Photographs, Photoprints, Other People (Box-folder 8/27)
  - Library of Congress, 1933-1984, undated see also Engel, Carl (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Löwenberg (Paul) Collection see Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.
  - Lotichius, Dietrich, 1972, undated (Box-folder 9/2)
  - "L" miscellaneous (Box-folder 9/3)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1941-1977 (Box-folder 9/4)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1972 (Box-folder 33/2)
  - Malipiero, Gian Francesco see Music, Ricercari per andici instrumenti
  - Malipiero, Riccardo, 1972, undated (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Menotti, Gian Carlo, 1956 (Box-folder 9/6)